Mss.Ms.Coll.30
American Philosophical Society
William Shedrick Willis papers, [ca. 1940-1983]
Circa 1940-1983
Mss.Ms.Coll.30
American Philosophical Society
13.0 Linear feet
William S. Willis Jr. (1921-1983), anthropologist and ethnohistorian, contributed significantly to the understanding of the dynamics of inter-cultural exchange in a multicultural context. After receiving his doctorate from Columbia University, he was hired as the first African American professor of Anthropology at Southern Methodist University. Upon resigning in protest from SMU in 1972, he returned to teach at Columbia University until 1975. His final years were spent studying Boasian anthropology. The collection includes correspondence, lecture notes, manuscripts of Willis' writings, and working notes. Of note, are the memos concerning his leaving Southern Methodist University and his extensive research notes on Franz Boas' views on race relations in America.
Willis, William Shedrick,1921-
Box 1-26
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Presented by Mrs. William S. Willis and accessioned, 12/21/1984 (1985 186ms).
Biographical/Historical note
William Shedrick Willis, Jr. (1921-1983) was an anthropologist and ethnohistorian. Shortly after his birth in Waco, Texas, the Willis family moved to Dallas where William graduated from Booker T. Washington High School. He continued his education at Howard University, graduating cum laude (A.B.,1942), and at Columbia University, where he recived a Ph.D. in anthropology in 1955. William married Georgina Upshur, who also attended Columbia University (M.S., 1946), in 1949.
Willis' early works addressed the subject of Indian-Black relations in Southeastern North America. His published works on this subject include Colonial Conflict and the Cherokee Indians, 1710-1760 (1955), The Nation of Bread (1957), Patrilineal Institutions in Southeastern North America (1963), and Divide and Rule: Red, White, and Black in the Southeast (1963).
After many years in New York City, the Willis' returned to Dallas in 1964. Here William accepted a joint teaching position in the Division of Social Sciences at Bishop College and in the Department of Sociology and Anthropology at Southern Methodist University. William Willis was the first Black scholar to be appointed to the faculty of Southern Methodist University.
It was during his tenure at SMU that Willia turned his attention to the study of Blacks in anthropology. In fact, Willis was instrumental in helping to establish the African American Studies Program at SMU. This new direction prompted Willis to re-evaluate the contribution of Franz Boas in relation to Blacks and the development of anthropology in the United States. Willis' works on these subjects include Anthropology and Negroes on the Southern Colonial Frontier (1970), and Skeletons in the Anthropological Closet (1972).
Willis resigned from SMU in 1972 in protest against the racist treatment he received from the faculty within the Department of Anthropology. He continued teaching at Columbia University during summer sessions until 1975. It was after his resignation from SMU that Willis began extensive research and writing on Franz Boas. The Willis' returned to Philadelphia (Georgine Willis' hometown) in 1978 where William was able to utilize the collections at the American Philosophical Society Library. Works during this period include Franz Boas and the Study of Black Folklore (1973), and Dubious Boasiana (1983).
William Willis suffered a fatal heart attack on 8 August 1983. He had begun writing a treatise entitled Boas Goes to Atalnta, which focused in Boas' commencement address at the 11th Atlanta University Conference on Negro Problems and its significance to Boas and the development of anthropology in the United States.
Willis was a fellow of the American Anthropological Association and the American Association for the Advancement of Science, ans was an active member of the American Society for Ethnohistory, the Society for American Archaeology, and the American Association of University Professors.
African American History Note
In addition to providing insight into the life of an African American scholar during the civil rights era, this collection may afford students of African American history useful information in a number of areas of interest.
Of special note are the lecture materials on the courses Willis taught in anthropology, history of anthropology, and African American studies, while at SMU and at summer sessions at Columbia University during the 1960s-1970s.
Scope and Contents note
The papers reflect Dr. Willis' passionate commitment to the field of anthropology and his significant contribution to the understanding of the dynamics of inter-cultural exchange in a multicultural context. With his study of Cherokee Indians; Southern Blacks and Native Americans; and Boasian anthropology, he extended the concept of cultural conditioning. His professional correspondence present his thoughts on the conflicts within the anthropological discipline; plus memos of the treatment he received as the first African American professor hired by Southern Methodist University. Lecture notes include classes taught at Southern Methodist University (1964-1972) and Columbia University (1972-1975). Of particular note are the extensive research notes on Franz Boas' attempts to deal with the race issue in America and his preservation of Black folklore.
The papers (26 boxes; 13 linear feet) are divided into four series:
Series I. Correspondence 1945-1983 3.5 linear feet Series II. Lecture and Research notes 1945-1983 8 linear feet Series III. Works 1955-1983 1 linear foot Series IV. Photographs and Ephemera 1942-1984 0.5 linear feet
Benedict, Ruth, 1887-1848; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942; Columbia University -- Faculty.; Columbia University -- Students.; Herzog, George, 1901-1983; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960; Linton, Ralph, 1893-1953; Mintz, Sidney Wilfred, 1922-; Southern Methodist University -- Faculty.; Steward, Julian Haynes, 1902-1972; Strong, William Duncan, 1899-1962.; Sturtevant, William C.; Wagley, Charles, 1913-; Weltfish, Gene, 1902-; White, Leslie A., 1900-1975.; Abolition, emancipation, freedom; African Americans--Study and teaching; Anthropology; Anthropology, ethnography, fieldwork; Anthropology--History; Civil rights; Culture, community, organizations; Labor, industrialization; Plantations; Race, race relations, racism; Reconstruction; Religion, religious organizations; Segregation; Slaves, slavery, slave trade; Social conditions, social advocacy, social reform
- Series I. Correspondence and Academic Papers, 1945-1983; 3.5 linear ft.
  - Abrahams, Norbert, 1972
  - African American Association, 1969
  - Alden, John R., 1952
  - Aldine Publishing Company, 1968-1969
  - Alexander, Lee G., 1972-1977
  - American Airlines, 1966
  - American Anthropological Association, 1969-1983
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1974-1984
  - American Association of University Professors, 1967
  - American Ethnological Society, 1972-1975
  - American Historical Association, 1970
  - American Museum of Natural History, 1963
  - American Philosophical Society, 1972-1983
  - American Railway Car Institute Library, 1974
  - American Society for Ethnohistory, 1970-1971
  - Anderson, Robert T., 1969
  - Aptheker, Herbert, 1970
  - Arlington State College, 1966
  - Association of Black Anthropologists, 1977
  - Atheneum, 1969
  - Bacote, C.A., 1974
  - Balima, Salfo Albert, 1968
  - Barnes, Annie S., 1973
  - Baruch College, 1969-1970
  - Basic Books, Inc., 1969
  - Bishop College, 1965-1970
  - Boas, Franziska, 1973
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company, Inc., 1969
  - Bond, George, 1969
  - Boston University, 1955
  - British Museum Library, 1963
  - Braun, Judy, 1973
  - Brody, Erness Bright, 1978
  - Brooks, Laurence F. LeB., 1970-1971
  - Butler Hall Apartments, 1971-1975
  - California State College, Hayward, 1969-1970
  - Cards--Christmas, Congratulations, Easter, 1965-1975
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington, 1964-1977
  - Carrington, Ulrich, 1969
  - Carte Blanche, 1971
  - Carter, Clarence E., 1951
  - Chalfort, Stuart, 1957
  - Charleston Library Society, 1964
  - Chase, Allan, 1972
  - Chicago Historical Society, 1952
  - City College, New York City, 1959-1967
  - Christian Fellowships, 1965
  - Clements Library, 1952-1957
  - Coe, Pamela, 1960
  - Cole, Douglas, 1982-1984
  - Collins, John, 1967-1976
  - Columbia University--Academic Record, 1945-1955
  - Columbia University--Administration, 1957-1983
  - Columbia University--Anthropology Department, n.d.
  - Columbia University--Courses, 1958-1969
  - Columbia University--Courses, 1970-1975
  - Columbia University--Students, 1959-1970
  - Cook, Edwin A., 1968
  - Cornish, James V., 1970-1973
  - Crane, Verner W., 1952
  - Thomas Y. Crowell Company, 1968-1971
  - Current Anthropology, 1969
  - Dallas--Charitable Organizations and Groups, 1964-1970
  - Dallas--Miscellaneous, 1965-1972
  - Dallas--Schools, 1966-1969
  - Dallas--Wayfarer, 1968
  - Darnell, Regna, 1973
  - Devereux, George, 1963
  - Diamond, Stanley, 1975-1979
  - Dibble, Wilhelmina L., 1942
  - Dougherty, Molly C., 1970
  - Downing, R. Scott, 1967
  - Dunnigan, Timothy, 1969
  - Eche, Eleanor B., 1971-1972
  - Ethnohistory, 1951-1970
  - Ethnology, 1962
  - Fairbanks, Charles H., 1963-1981
  - Fauset, Arthur Huff, 1973-1974
  - Fenton, William N., 1957
  - Ford Foundation Foreign Area Fellowships, 1956-1957
  - Foster, George M., 1969-1971
  - Franklin, W. Neil, 1952
  - Fredrickson, George M., 1972
  - Free Press, 1969
  - Fried, Morton H., 1964-1972
  - Fried, Morton H., 1973-1983
  - Funcion, Peggy, n.d.
  - Furcrou, Tom, 1968
  - Gallagher, James P., 1970-1983
  - Garrett, Joi Anne, 1971-1973
  - Gavronsky, Serge, 1968
  - Gelber, S. Michael, n.d.
  - Gilmore, Kathleen, 1968
  - Glenn, James L., 1968
  - Gonzales, Ambrose E., 1969
  - Gotham Book Mart, 1942
  - Gradwohl, David M., 1966
  - Greenwood Press, 1983
  - Gregory, Hiram F., 1970-1981
  - Grove Press, Inc., 1969
  - Guggenheim Foundation, 1970-1976
  - Handbook of American Indians, 1983-1988
  - Harlan, Louis R., 1973-1974
  - Harper and Row, 1967
  - Harper's Corner, 1969
  - Harris, Joe P., 1969-1971
  - Harris, Marvin, 1967-1981
  - Harris, R.K., 1966
  - Harrison, Ira E., 1983-1984
  - Harvard University Library, 1958-1974
  - Haynes, Leonard L., Jr., 1967
  - Hickerson, Harold, 1968
  - Hirabayashi, James A., 1969
  - Hochstein, Edward, 1967-1968
  - Hockaday School, 1968-1969
  - Hook, Sidney, 1968
  - Hope, Clare, 1971
  - Hopkins, May Agness, 1965
  - Howard University, 1941-1975
  - Hoxie, Fred, 1975
  - Hsu, Francis L.K., 1972
  - Hudson's Bay Company, 1952
  - Humanities Press, 1966
  - Hymes, Dell, 1971-1976
  - Illinois State University, 1967-1969
  - International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences, 1972
  - Jacobs, Wilbur R., 1957
  - Jay, Edward J., 1969
  - Jelks, Edward, Mr. and Mrs., 1966-1983
  - Journal of Negro History, 1962-1973
  - Kansas State University, 1968
  - Kilpatrick, Jack Frederick, 1967
  - King, H. Gill, 1975
  - King, Morton B., 1966-1970
  - Klein, A. Norman, 1971
  - Koenig, Harriet, 1969
  - Knapp, Robert L., 1972-1973
  - Lafayette College, 1960-1961
  - Leacock, Eleanor, 1954
  - Leap, William L., 1970-1975
  - Library of Congress, 1952-1963
  - Lieban, Richard W., 1974-1977
  - Little, Brown and Company, 1969
  - Locke, Alain, 1944-1946
  - Logan, Rayford W., 1940-1967
  - Logan, Rayford W., 1968-1972
  - McAlister, L.N., 1964
  - McAllister, Gilbert, 1970
  - McDowell, Ellis E., Mrs., 1970
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1966
  - Macmillan Company, 1965-1969
  - McNeil, Pearl, 1975
  - Mahon, John K., 1968-1969
  - Manners, Robert A., 1963
  - Marable, Ashley, 1970-1971
  - Marietta College, 1967
  - Martin, Mary G., 1958
  - Martin, Peter, 1970-1972
  - Martinez Brothers, 1968
  - Medgar Evers College, 1972
  - Mercantile National Bank, 1957-1971
  - Metzger, Walter P., 1969-1973
  - Miami University, 1971
  - Mintz, Sidney W., 1963-1983
  - Miscellaneous, 1967-1970
  - Mitchell, Howard E., 1963
  - Moravian Archives, 1952
  - Morgan State College, 1957
  - Murdoch, Richard K., 1965
  - Murphy, Robert F., 1969-1983
  - Nagenda, John, 1965
  - Neal, Ernest E., 1952
  - National Archives, 1956
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1970-1971
  - National Science Foundation, 1957
  - New School for Social Research, 1970
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1969
  - New York Historical Society, 1952
  - Newark State College, 1969
  - Newberry Library, 1960-1965
  - Nickerson, Gifford S., 1964
  - Norbeck, Edward, 1968
  - North Texas State University, 1969
  - Northwestern University, 1955
  - Northwestern University Library, 1974
  - Nye, Hermes, Mrs., 1968
  - Odden, Allen, 1968-1972
  - Odyssey Series, 1979-1980
  - Oniang'o, Clement M.P., 1973-1974
  - Ostrom, Allen and Sonya, 1970
  - Oxford University Press, 1967
  - Packard, Barbara, 1967-1970
  - Palmatary, Helen C., 1968
  - Pan American Union, 1965-1969
  - Pantheon Books, 1972-1974
  - Parker, George, III, 1971
  - Parker, Theodore J. Kwaku, 1974
  - Peacock, Clarence, 1958
  - Porter, Kenneth W., 1972
  - Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, 1952
  - Phelps-Stokes Fund, 1960
  - Post Tribune, 1968
  - Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1965
  - Price, Richard, 1974-1982
  - Quadrangle Books, Inc., 1970
  - Quinnipiac College, 1972
  - Random House, Inc., 1965-1969
  - Ritcheson, Charles, 1969
  - Robichaud, Gerard, 1974
  - Rockefeller Family and Associates, 1972-1973
  - Rose, Dan, 1971
  - Rubin, Vera, 1965-1968
  - Rubottom, R. Richard, Jr., 1967-1977
  - San Jose State College, 1969
  - Sapir, David, 1975
  - Schechter, Elaine J., 1975-1976
  - Schulte, Bob, 1972-1977
  - Seidenberg, Steven, 1983
  - Service, Elman R., 1963-1966
  - Shack, William A., 1971
  - Shuffler, R. Henderson, 1966
  - Simkins, Alice, 1966
  - Simon, Melly, 1960
  - Skinner, Elliott P., 1965-1968; #1
  - Skinner, Elliott P., 1969-1974; #2
  - Skinner, Elliott P., 1976-1977; #3
  - Smith, Jack O., 1968
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1963-1975
  - Social Education, 1968
  - Social Science Research Council, 1970-1973
  - Society for American Archaeology, 1965
  - Sonoma State College, 1970
  - South Carolina Archives, 1975
  - South Carolina Tricentennial Symposium, 1969
  - Southern Anthropological Society, 1966-1971
  - Southern Methodist University--Admissions Committee, 1969-1971
  - Southern Methodist University--Afro-American Studies Program, 1969-1971
  - Southern Methodist University--Assembly, 1966
  - Southern Methodist University--Committees, 1967-1971
  - Southern Methodist University--Conferences, Seminars, Symposia, 1968-1971
  - Southern Methodist University--Course Evaluations, 1970-1971; #1
  - Southern Methodist University--Course Evaluations, 1970-1971; #2
  - Southern Methodist University--Course outlines and content, 1966-1971
  - Southern Methodist University--Course Rosters, 1966-1971
  - Southern Methodist University--Course Schedules, 1965-1971
  - Southern Methodist University--Examinations, 1965-1970
  - Southern Methodist University--Faculty Lists, 1970
  - Southern Methodist University--Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1965-1971
  - Southern Methodist University--General memos, Administration, 1965-1971
  - Southern Methodist University--General memos, Courses and requirements
  - Southern Methodist University--General memos, Department of Anthropology, 1966-1969
  - Southern Methodist University--General memos, Department of Anthropology, 1970
  - Southern Methodist University--General memos, Department of Anthropology, 1971
  - Southern Methodist University--General memos, Department of Anthropology, 1972
  - Southern Methodist University--General memos, University Policies and Organization, 1966-1971
  - Southern Methodist University--Guest Lectures and Candidates, 1966-1970
  - Southern Methodist University--Ibero-American Program, 1967-1971
  - Southern Methodist University--Invitations, 1966-1970
  - Southern Methodist University--Materials gathered by Georgine Willis, 1967-1969
  - Southern Methodist University--Materials gathered by Georgine Willis, 1970
  - Southern Methodist University--Materials gathered by Georgine Willis, 1971
  - Southern Methodist University--The Mustang, 1965
  - Southern Methodist University--National Science Foundation Grant Proposal, 1969-1971
  - Southern Methodist University--Organizations, 1967-1970
  - Southern Methodist University--Schools, miscellaneous, 1966-1971
  - Southern Methodist University--Students, 1966-1972
  - Southern Methodist University--Students, Recommendations, 1968-1974
  - Southern Methodist University--Sustentation Campaign, 1966-1969
  - Southern Methodist University--University Relations, 1970-1971
  - Southern Methodist University--William S. Willis, Jr. Appointment, 1965-1970
  - Southwest Museum, 1974
  - Southwestern Journal of Anthropology, 1962-1965
  - State University of New York--Purchase and Stony Brook, 1968-1970
  - Steward, Julian H., 1967
  - Stocking, George, 1970-1972
  - Sturtevant, William, 1967-1983
  - Swanton, John R., 1949-1952
  - Swarthmore College, 1970
  - Swift, Mildred D., 1972-1973
  - Syracuse University--Maxwell School, 1971
  - Szwed, John, 1971-1972
  - Taylor, Hobart, Jr., 1965-1967
  - Telephone messages, 1966-1972
  - Texas Academy of Science, 1965
  - Thompson, William S., 1969
  - Thurman, H., 1942
  - Tolbert, Thomas, 1970
  - Twyford, Edna, 1965
  - Union Theological Seminary Library, 1974
  - University of Buffalo, 1957
  - University of California Press, 1966-1969
  - University of Chicago, 1944-1970
  - University of Florida--Florida State Museum, 1963
  - University of Illinois--Chicago Circle and Urbana, 1971-1973
  - University of Massachusetts Library, 1973-1976
  - University of Miami, 1970
  - University of Michigan, 1944-1969
  - University of Montana, 1967
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1980
  - University of South Carolina Press, 1970
  - University of South Florida, 1971
  - University of Tennessee Press, 1971
  - University of Texas, 1968-1983
  - University of Texas Press, 1968-1970
  - University of Washington Press, 1969
  - University of Wisconsin, 1957
  - Vayda, Andrew P., 1967-1971
  - Vogel, Robert C., 1977
  - Wagley, Charles, 1958-1974
  - Wallace, Anthony F.C., 1963
  - Wallace, Ben J., 1969
  - Wayne University, 1955-1956
  - Weiss, Winnie, 1970-1975
  - Weltfish, Gene--Festschrift, 1976
  - Wendorf, Fred, 1967-1968
  - Western Washington State College, 1970
  - White, David, 1972
  - White, Leslie A., 1948
  - White, Philip A., 1963-1977
  - John Hay Whitney Foundation, 1965-1972
  - Who's Who in Texas Today, 1967
  - Williams, Eddie N., 1966
  - Williams, Franklin H., 1969
  - Willie, Charles V., 1971-1974
  - Willis, Georgine, 1949-1970
  - Willis, William S., Jr.--Biographical materials, 1983-1984
  - Wolf, Eric R., 1983
  - Wood, Peter H., 1971-1974
  - Woodbury, Richard B., 1969
  - Wright, R.R., 1970
  - Yale University--Press and Library, 1969-1973
- Series II. Lecture and Research Notes, 8 linear ft.
  - Lecture notes--Contemporary Anthropological Theory, 1950
  - Lecture notes--Cultural Dynamics, 1948; #1
  - Lecture notes--Cultural Dynamics, n.d.; #2
  - Lecture notes--Cultural of Contemporary Brazil, 1949
  - Lecture notes--Energy and Evolutionary Culture, 1948
  - Lecture notes--General Anthropology
  - Lecture notes--Great Plains, 1959
  - Lecture notes--History of Ethnological Theory, 1946
  - Lecture notes--Human Biology, 1946
  - Lecture notes--Imperialism and World Politics, 1954
  - Lecture notes--Indians of the Greater Southwest, #1
  - Lecture notes--Indians of the Greater Southwest, #2
  - Lecture notes--Indians of the Greater Southwest, #3
  - Lecture notes--Interpretation of Pueblo Culture, n.d.
  - Lecture notes--Miscellaneous Charts, n.d.
  - Lecture notes--Mythology, 1945-1946
  - Lecture notes--Nature of Culture, 1948
  - Lecture notes--Negro Africa, 1956
  - Lecture notes--Negro in the New World, 1956
  - Lecture notes--Origin of the American Indian, #1
  - Lecture notes--Origin of the American Indian, #2
  - Lecture notes--Origin of the American Indian, #3
  - Lecture notes--Peoples of Africa, 1945-1946
  - Lecture notes--Personality and Culture, 1946
  - Lecture notes--Population, 1948
  - Lecture notes--Primitive languages, 1946
  - Lecture notes--Race Mixture, 1948
  - Lecture notes--Religion, 1946
  - Lecture notes--Social Organization, 1946; #1
  - Lecture notes--Social Organization, 1949; #2
  - Lecture notes--South America, 1947; #1
  - Lecture notes--South America, 1947; #2
  - Lecture notes--South America, 1947; #3
  - Lecture notes--Sudan, 1948-1949
  - Lecture notes--Theory, 1948; #1
    Steward, Julian Haynes, 1902-1972
  - Lecture notes--Theory, 1948; #2
    White, Leslie A., 1900-1972
  - Lecture notes--Theory, 1949; #3
  - Lecture notes--Given at Columbia University, 1971; #1
  - Lecture notes--Given at Columbia University, 1973-1974; #2
  - Lecture notes--Given at Columbia University, 1975; #3
  - Lecture notes--Given at Columbia University, n.d.; #4
  - Lecture notes--Given at Columbia University, n.d.; #5
  - Lecture notes--Given at Columbia University, n.d.; #6
  - Notebooks, n.d.; 2.0 Volume(s)
  - Research notes--Annotated volumes, 6.0 Volume(s)
  - Research notes--American Eugenics Society
  - Research notes--American Eugenics Society--Frederick Osborn
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Thelma Adamson
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Ethal Aginsky
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Robert T. Aitken
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--M. J. Andrade
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--M. F. Ashley-Montagu
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Julia Averkieva
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--S. A. Barrett
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Ruth Benedict
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Black Africans, #1
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Black Africans, #2
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Boas and Blacks/Guggenheim Proposals
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Boas goes to Atlanta, #1
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Boas goes to Atlanta, #2
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Boas goes to Atlanta, #3
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Boas goes to Atlanta, #4
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--W. Bogoras
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Anita Brenner
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Sara W. Brown
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Ruth L. Bunzel
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Mabel Carney
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Fay Cooper Cole, #1
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Correspondence, #1
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Correspondence, #2
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Correspondence, #3
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Ella C. Deloria
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Akintunde Dipeolu
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--W. E. B. DuBois
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--L. C. Dunn
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Theresa M. Durlach
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--David Efron
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--George W. Ellis
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--N. A. Fadipe
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Reo F. Fortune
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--L. Foster
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Manuel Gamio
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Viola E. Garfield
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--General notes, #1
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--General notes, #2
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--General notes, #3
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--General notes, #4
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--General notes, #5
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--General notes, #6
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--General notes, #7
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--General notes, #8
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--General notes, #9
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--General notes, #10
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--General notes, #11
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--General notes, #12
  - Research notes--Franz Boas--Herman Haeberlin